<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-10T11:05:25-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">We Are Generation Z.</title><subtitle>We will be heard.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">On Sexual Racism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Donald.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Sexual Racism" /><published>2020-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Donald</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Donald.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s just past midnight. The dim glow of an iPhone is the only light in the room. A thumb swipes routinely swipes upward. After thirty seconds, the grid ends. “UNLOCK MORE GUYS.” Almost mechanically, the thumb taps the top of the screen and the process repeats. All the while, while the body operates free of cognition, there is a little voice screaming in my head: delete your fucking grindr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the many things to be said of 2020, I find one sentiment universally relatable: this year has asked a lot of us. In battling both a global pandemic and systemic racial injustice, all of us have had to exert some additional labor, be it emotional or physical. This means that many of us are also trying to check-out when we can. A good book, a netflix binge, or a long yoga session can be a great opportunity for some solo escapism, but we sometimes need a little community, too. For many queer men and trans/non-binary folks, Grindr has long served such a purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grindr continues to urge users to stay home and stay safe, but in a remote world, it has done all it can to keep people connected. In addition to its being an online hub for gay networking, flirting, and dating, Grindr has added virtual events suich as drag shows and celebrity interviews. On its surface, it’s the perfect place for people to coalesce around a shared culture, feel safe, and maybe even share that quarantine booty pic. However, for many queer people of color (QPOC), Grindr all too often contributes to the alienatation from which we are trying to find shelter. The reason? Grindr dudes are really racist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a new phenomenon. Since its release in 2009, the app has ultimately been seen as a venue for men to advertise their sexual preferences in hopes of finding their Mr. Right Now. Almost immediately, these preferences were racialized or otherwise discriminatory. Depending on your location, sometimes more than half of user profiles will have a “wish list”, explicitly stating either an interest in or aversion to such categories as “fatties,” “femmes,” “Asians,” and “Blacks.” In fact, such preferencing and objectification is prevalent enough to have inspired the creation of a website to call out those who perpetuate it. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.douchebagsofgrindr.com/&quot;&gt;‘Douchebags of Grindr’&lt;/a&gt; is a mural of profiles all displaying some sort of sexual discrimination (e.g. “Please be white”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remarkably, this fails to strike many people as problematic. One user, interviewed for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vice.com/sv/article/bnpavv/so-many-gay-dudes-are-depressingly-racist-on-dating-apps&quot;&gt;VICE article on sexual racism&lt;/a&gt;, perfectly sums up the plea to innocence of so many men on Grindr: “If someone actually cannot get turned on by someone from a minority group, that’s not really something they can change.” As if it were a factor as inconsequential as height or hair color, many people see racial preferencing as simply another component of someone’s “type.” However, height is not a line along which the systematic allocation of resources has been determined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Denton Callendar, a social scientist &lt;a href=&quot;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10508-015-0487-3&quot;&gt;who studied the correlation between sexual racism and generalized racism&lt;/a&gt;, explains, “sexual racism is a form of racism because, quite simply, it is the use of racial stereotypes to include or exclude groups of people. The reality is that our desires—like all of our thoughts and behaviours—are as susceptible to broader social and political trends.” This means that your attraction, or lack thereof, to a particular race is not some innate preference, but a prejudiced learned over a lifetime of socialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also means that the harm done to Grindr users of color is just as visceral as that which we experience from other racist interactions. In fact, between the intimacy of the setting and the vulnerability around human sexuality, oftentimes it can be sexual racism that is the most damning to a person of color’s psyche. And this doesn’t just mean negative racialized comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Positive racial preferencing, referred to as racial fetishization, is just as much an arm of sexual racism. Terms like jungle or yellow fever are thinly veiled attempts to reduce individuals down to racialized aspects of their appearance so that they can fulfil some sort of sexual fantasy. By fixating on a sex partners skin color or associate stereotypes, QPOC are being othered in a sexual way. There’s a pretty thick line between attraction and fetishization, and comments like “BBC” and “Sub Asian Bottom” usually indicate which side of that line you’re on (hint: it’s the racist side).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is always surprising to me how fiercely queer men will commit to their racial preferences. Usually these men are white, but sexual racism reverberates through many racial communities on the app. Either way, queer men are continuously unable or unwilling to acknowledge their racism or the harm that their racial preferences can cause to queers of color on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this way, for QPOC, Grindr and similar queer social networking apps have become somewhat of a double edge sword. In a remote world, these apps present some of the only avenues for community, connection, and companionship. On the other hand, consistently dealing with sexual racism can leave us feeling smaller and more alienated than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, acknowledging the problem is not enough. As the recent surge of organized resistance to racial inequality should make clear, change will only follow rigorous and collective accountability. In a recent twitter thread, Guardian and BBC News writer Alexander Leon offers a series of infographics about sexual racism, including what you can do to combat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ibb.co/m4YHqH6&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/89Rj5j6/donald-inline.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;donald-inline&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it may be unrealistic to expect every Grindr user to change over night, so it’s about time Grindr and other social media companies treated sexual racism the same way that they do other forms of racism. To be fair, many of Grindr’s recent events and panels have been aimed at sparking dialogue about racial inequality. Yet that users are still permitted to publicly display their distaste for Black and brown sex partners should remind us that conversations can never replace accountability.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>donald</name></author><summary type="html">It’s just past midnight. The dim glow of an iPhone is the only light in the room. A thumb swipes routinely swipes upward. After thirty seconds, the grid ends. “UNLOCK MORE GUYS.” Almost mechanically, the thumb taps the top of the screen and the process repeats. All the while, while the body operates free of cognition, there is a little voice screaming in my head: delete your fucking grindr.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Erasing The Stigma: One Man’s Battle with Mental Health</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lucas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Erasing The Stigma: One Man's Battle with Mental Health" /><published>2020-07-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lucas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lucas.html">&lt;p&gt;Staring at its seductive curves and edges, I was entranced. It offered a glimmer of hope and redemption in my current state of anguish and depression. The object was a recently sharpened Japanese knife, and one clean slice could set me free. Just one cut could launch me into oblivion and rip off the tight armor of pain encased around my body. This enticing thought would tantalize me multiple times a day. Whenever I would be doing something, no matter how distracting, my taunting self-critic would make his way into my mind: “You have absolutely nothing to offer this world — all you are is a walking failure. How are you such a fucking pussy? Are you really going to cry all day? Just kill yourself already.” No matter how convincing this voice was, I always thought of my friends and family. My sister and mother would be plunged into a permanent world of pain and misery if I went through with this destructive mission. Why would I want to make them feel like I did then? I would not wish that despair upon my worst enemy. If it weren’t for them, I would not be alive today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a viewer’s vantage, I’ve led a charmed life. I am smart, healthy, attractive, wealthy, and fun to be around. People would continuously seek my company; beautiful women were frequently confessing their feelings to me. This is undoubtedly an incredibly privileged lifestyle. But it was all an act; one worth a fucking Oscar and a Golden Globe. Due to my high EQ, I had the dating game down to a perfect science. Distance was my sword and mysteriousness was my shield; I used those tools like a hungry soldier ready for war. I presented girls with the image of who I wanted to be, not who I truly was. Whenever I showed them the highly sensitive, insecure, needy boy with abandonment issues, they would run away and leave me devastated. Since revealing the real me always resulted in misery, why do it? Although taking on this persona got me plenty of romantic success, this performance left me feeling both empty and tremendously guilty. I could not be my true self around the girl I loved because I knew it would push her away. That sad reality warped through my mind whenever we spent time together; however, it was masqueraded by the charming, cheerful, and entertaining character I was presenting. This rule did not only apply to girls; I presented a fake version of myself to friends as well. I grew up as a chubby, hispanic kid in a posh, British school: this was a losing formula for making friends. This issue transferred to high school. Although I had a core group of brothers that I consider family to this day, every girl I wanted to make friends with or was romantically interested in pushed me away. Often, when I talked to them, I would freeze and stutter due to the bullying I had received growing up. By the time I got to college, I had realized that being myself got me nowhere, so I put on a shiny fucking mask in every social endeavor. I quickly climbed the social ranks and became the “it” guy on campus, but knowing I had to fake my way to get there killed me every night. I was in way too deep. When I got home most nights, I stared at myself in the mirror and dissected every little thing about my body and mind. Every time, I saw my ten-year-old self in London, laughing and kicking a ball around, delicate and pudgy with a smile that melted hearts. Tears rolled down my face as I longed to embrace him tightly and tell him that everything would be ok, but I couldn’t. All I wanted to be was a role model for him and show him that things would work out for the better. But that was the beginning of the end for him. Insecurities would blister his mind, abandonment would constantly break his heart, and bullying would carve out his soul. This only got worse over time. About a year ago, I would stand over a secret ledge in my school as I looked down and prayed I would trip and fall — every fucking day. This is when I finally realized that I needed serious help. Due to my well crafted facade, no one had a clue what was going on inside. All that pain was locked in a vault and the key was nowhere to be found. No matter how much pain someone is in, people can become masters of disguise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked into my first session with my psychiatrist feeling utterly defeated. The years of toxic masculinity imprinted in my mind made me think I must be crazy and less of a man for seeking help. I stared into my doctor’s eyes blankly as she told me I had severe anxiety and depression, as well as ADHD. White noise played in my mind for the next few hours; I could not formulate a single thought. Later, I intently observed the ranting, homeless man running around Union Square, thinking that could be my future. Within three months, I was on seven medications: two antidepressants, two anxiety medications, two ADHD medications, and benzos on the side. I felt like a complete zombie. Although being numb has its benefits, I could not feel any form of excitement, love, or positivity. However much pain I used to feel, the wave of chills when I heard a good song or the warm buzz when kissing a crush made it all momentarily vanish. There was nothing like those moments; they would replay in my mind whenever I was feeling down. But now, even sex felt like a chore; I went through the motions without feeling a single thing in my body. Music became nothing but sound, offering no euphoria or escape. Friends would ask me to hang out, girls would ask me to get drinks, but I could not bring myself to join them. I felt invisible and worthless. Who would want to hang out with someone this lifeless? In comes alcohol and weed, which became lethal in combination with the medicine I was on. After a couple glasses of Japanese whiskey and some tightly rolled joints, my unconscious was released and the loving, cute, bubbly ten-year old Lucas came flying out, and I loved it. I had relentless energy and confidence; I felt like I was on top of the world. In those inebriated moments, life felt easy and I had no desire to end it. That would all come crashing down when I was violently fingering my throat at the end of most nights as the walls were caving in. That momentary bliss resulted in two days of pain, depression, and intense suicidal ideations as penance. The combination of benzos, alcohol, and marijuana made my brain feel like someone tossed it in a blender on the highest speed. I still feel the effects of this concoction to this day. Nevertheless, as soon as a friend called, I popped the bottle open and fired another blunt — a vicious cycle with no end in sight. Although I was hellbent on continuing this path of destruction, my mother thankfully intervened and encouraged me to find another psychiatrist who did not enable this sort of behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doctor was my last chance. I was worried that if this did not work, that might be it for me. But luckily this time, I found the right match. After extensive discussions and research, he concluded that I have bipolar type II disorder, which my previous psychiatrist had failed to see. Although well-intentioned, her drug cocktail exacerbated my issues and chemically made my suicidal ideations come at a much higher frequency. After three weeks of the worst withdrawals I have ever been through and, at times, unbearably strong suicidal urges, I came out on the other side. I feel happy, grounded, focused, and like myself for the first time since I was a child. All it took was one good doctor, a caring mother, and a willingness to change. Furthermore, I am off all anxiety and ADHD meds, as well as weed and alcohol. All I take now is Lithium, a mood balancer for people with bipolar disorder. However, not taking the anxiety and ADHD meds requires a high level of discipline. I still have anxiety and struggle with maintaining focus, but for these issues, drugs are not the answer, at least not for me. The natural medicines I now take are supplements, intense daily workouts, an hour of meditation, and a strict diet curtailed to my needs. I also aim to be sober from drugs and alcohol for the rest of my life. This regiment is by no means facile, but I never want to go back to feeling like that zombie again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life does not have to be a constant cycle of suffering and anxiety. Each of us has the power to break free from our pain and start fresh. Trust me; I know this is no easy path. I spent years walking down that endless road of misery, continually asking myself when enough was enough. Although men have advantages in many ways, in America, men committed suicide 3.6 times more often than women in 2018 and white men accounted for about 70% of suicide deaths. It’s my sense that this is due to a deep-rooted culture of toxic masculinity. In an effort to stay strong and not seem too effeminate, men refuse to talk about this shit: “Don’t be a bitch.” They keep their demons locked in a cage and refuse to give them attention. However, the longer they stay neglected, the quicker they grow. This mental strategy leads men to choose death as a route to deal with their pain. They simply can not imagine another way out. Not even a year ago, that was me. I could have been part of those statistics. Seek help. Seek guidance. Seek love. If you are scared of seeming crazy and being discredited, I was in the same situation. I beg you; please take a chance on yourself. Yes, I am bipolar. Yes, you may think I am crazy. However, I do not give a shit. I can finally accept who I truly am, and I fucking love that guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There is no genius without a touch of madness” (Seneca).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to our incredibly fucked up culture and government, therapy is a privilege that not all can afford or even fathom going through with. Here are some places that can guide one to getting free or affordable therapy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;National Suicide Prevention Lifeline 800–273-TALK (8255)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.mhanational.org/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.mentalhealth.gov/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.thetrevorproject.org/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://www.crisistextline.org/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://wearemore.life/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://blahtherapy.com/&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>lucas</name></author><summary type="html">Staring at its seductive curves and edges, I was entranced. It offered a glimmer of hope and redemption in my current state of anguish and depression. The object was a recently sharpened Japanese knife, and one clean slice could set me free. Just one cut could launch me into oblivion and rip off the tight armor of pain encased around my body. This enticing thought would tantalize me multiple times a day. Whenever I would be doing something, no matter how distracting, my taunting self-critic would make his way into my mind: “You have absolutely nothing to offer this world — all you are is a walking failure. How are you such a fucking pussy? Are you really going to cry all day? Just kill yourself already.” No matter how convincing this voice was, I always thought of my friends and family. My sister and mother would be plunged into a permanent world of pain and misery if I went through with this destructive mission. Why would I want to make them feel like I did then? I would not wish that despair upon my worst enemy. If it weren’t for them, I would not be alive today.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unpacking Brown Boy Misogyny</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hiba.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unpacking Brown Boy Misogyny" /><published>2020-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hiba</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hiba.html">&lt;p&gt;Brown boys our age engage in the most violent projections of the patriarchy. The diaspora in New York City represents a microcosm of South Asia - its vibrancy, its colorful culture, but it rears the ugly head too often, whether it be divisions of religions, nationalism, or of course, a very carefully constructed misogyny. It doesn’t come from Islam, and yet religion is used as a defense from accountability. It doesn’t come from Hinduism, and yet tradition is used as a facade to get away with it. Stop using God as your security blanket to justify your suppression of women. It has stretched from our homelands that are desperately trying to reform to no avail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to break this down into three sections: Guilty, Mia Khalifa, Simping to make it easier to comprehend. It’s like a pyramid, top to bottom - the hierarchy of brown boy misogyny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GUILTY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past week or so, brown girls in New York City have been coming forward in what can be called an intense second wave of the #MeToo Movement. And this time, it’s coming for the brown boys who thought that our culture’s taboos would keep them safe. It’s not just random brown men either. It’s friends, it’s classmates, it’s family, it’s Khan’s Tutorial. Accounts like Telling My Truth, which was the first to go viral, are anonymously sharing the victim’s stories and urging their followers to hold the brown boy accountable for his actions. And they’re listening: in the past two days alone, there are thousands of comments tagging the said perpetrator’s school and employment in an effort to call attention to the specific story. As of this writing, Telling My Truth has been deactivated but To Be A Survivor and anon.co17 are still actively posting stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in classic brown culture style, we have men and even women, deflecting the issue, but let’s be honest, did we expect anything else? Instead of cutting ties with known rapists, these people are insisting that somehow it is still the girl’s fault. She was drunk. She was showing skin. She was hanging out with a guy late at night. “It’s haram,” they say. But what about forcing yourself onto someone? Is that not haram too? Prophet Muhammad (SAW) swiftly punished a rapist when a woman came to him. He did not try to convince her otherwise, he did not blame her - so who are you to gaslight a survivor? There in no link between rape and sexual desire. Don’t tell us to dress better - become better men. When the stories started to gain traction, brown boys claimed that these girls were ruining the man’s reputation. Did you not stop to think that he ruined her in every way imaginable? And what reputation are you talking about? Instead of standing with the victim, you’re out here defending your boy and asking her what she was doing. Who cares what she was doing? We know what he did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over and over again, we are seeing the brown boys named defending themselves by insisting that while they are definitely assholes, they are not rapists. They’re saying they had consent from someone who was DRUNK. How dare you. How do you expect someone who is intoxicated to give you the same answers as she would if she were sober? You were waiting for her to be drunk enough to have your way. Their excuses are: “She was wet too!” “I know she wanted it.” “She was feening for me.” “She’s a clout-chaser.” “She continued to be friends with me after I did it.” “How come she didn’t report it to the police?” “How do you not know when you were being raped?” Their pathetic excuses won’t work on us. Tell me, do you know that physical arousal isn’t consent? If she wanted it, why are you so scared? Was she really feening for you, or are you gaslighting the trauma you caused her? I hate to be the one to ask, but tell me, what clout could a rape survivor possibly get when our own president is a rapist? And since you’re so smart, you must know that thousands of rape kits go untested at police stations, right? You must know that police do nothing to protect women. And you, of course, know the lengths a brown family would go to convince their daughter not to report her abuser. It is not the job of brown girls to educate you on how survivors process rape differently, there is no ‘correct’ way to react after being assaulted. But since I’m on the topic anyway, let me tell you that 70% of rapists are committed by someone known to the victim and continuing a relationship with an abuser is a common way of repressing the memory. It does not, in any way or form, negate the fact that the rape happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the friends of these boys? They’re defending them. They’re writing love letters in their DMs as proof of character. News flash: just because he held the door open for you once in third grade doesn’t absolve of him of rape. Brown boys have collectively come together to force the victims to prove their rapes countless times. One girl even had to screenshot her rapist’s “apology” and refuted every single thing he said because he tampered with evidence and screenshots. Brown girls don’t owe it to anyone to prove a single thing. And yet, they’re being pressured to so they can relive their trauma under a harsh spotlight. These are brown boys that we might not know personally, but they run in our circles. We have heard these stories before. It could have been any of us, and it is imperative to stand up for all brown girls. Break the damn bro code, call out your boys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our culture downplays sexual assault because we are trained to believe that men are in control, and even if we know that men are the problem, we place the blame onto women because brown girls should compromise, be careful, and protect themselves. The shortcomings of brown men are somehow still our fault and ours to fix: jab iski biwi aayegi, toh yeh sudhar jayega (When he gets married, his wife will fix him). We never teach brown boys to not rape, we don’t teach them the word no. We let them get away with so much and it culminates into an explosion like the one happening right now, and it’s because of brown boys and their sense of entitlement, their overly inflated egos, and the failure of our culture to raise our men right. Our culture already makes women so vulnerable from the very moment they are born. The very first thing we’re told to do is close our legs, sit like a lady, cover yourself. Brown girls are already guilty from the time we step into this world. This is the very same reason why it is so frustrating and difficult to even say anything against an abuser, predator, and rapist - we are told to keep quiet because it won’t get anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the thing is, it doesn’t start with rape. Men view rape as aggressive, forced upon sex, but ignore the cat-calling, groping, and casual touches we deal with while we walk down Sutphin. I don’t know who needs to hear this but saying MashAllah won’t cancel out the fact that you tried to grab a girl’s ass. Every time I try to explain rape culture and its consequences, I am hit with the same answer: “I don’t care, it’s a joke.” These are the same boys that turn around and victimize themselves when they are finally called out for their extremely perverted behavior. Rape is not limited to extreme force - and brown boys are the quickest to victim-blame. Save for a select few, so many brown boys are now saying that there are two sides of the story and that we should all wait for evidence - were you not paying attention? How much more evidence do you need? If your first instinct when hearing about sexual assault is to automatically discredit the victim, or start to talk about how women “lie,” as if that false equivalency even makes sense, unlearn your own misogyny. Growing up in a close-minded household isn’t an excuse to not educate yourself. Brown boys never keep this same energy for the 98% of rape allegations that are true but will hound to death the 2% that are false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it’s just our culture that’s failed us for being inherently insensitive to gender-based violence  - it’s the men. They lack empathy, they lack remorse, and they want us to ‘stop the cap.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MIA KHALIFA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brown boys are more often than not desensitized to violence - baba beats ami, he slaps your sister across her face, but he doesn’t hit you because you’re a mard (man). You may get angry at him then, you may shout to tell him to stop, but the violence seeps in through your veins. It runs through your veins so viciously that you watch media that inflicts violence upon women and you don’t even notice - be it your video games, the Netflix shows you watch, and the unethical porn that you consume. Suddenly, all the sharam (shame) that you speak of dissipates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me make it a tiny bit more specific: let’s talk about Mia Khalifa. Let’s put a pin in the conversation about Islamophobia and her Christian Forces tattoo (yes, they’re the same armed forces who allied with the IDF and led the Sabra/Shatila Massacre). It was not her active decision to partake in hijabi porn, although it was disrespectful and sexualized Muslim women, and sure, let’s hold her accountable for calling the scenes satire, but let’s not pretend that’s where the sexualization of Muslim women by brown men started. She was coerced into her contract with Pornhub during a low point in her life years ago and was never compensated properly. Pornhub refuses to take down her videos.  But brown boys don’t know that. All you know is that she’s the ‘Muslim’ girl from porn and crack a joke about her every time you see a brown girl wear glasses. She lost her family, she doesn’t get a second chance at first impressions, and gets shamed every day all because brown boys have an extremely exploitative obsession with her. You call her a disgrace but you actively watch her videos (special shoutout for Muslim-majority countries for always ranking at the top for porn consumption) and then take pleasure in picking her apart in your little locker rooms. And it’s all because you have been taught (and you believe) a twisted culture that allows you to belittle any woman for any reason. Brown boys have the audacity to say that she chose to do porn, that it was her fault for ignoring how our traditions work, and then say it’s not a respectful job to have - why does it irk you when girls profit off their own sexualization? Learn the difference between coercion and consent, and secondly, our traditions are rooted in the patriarchy - brown girls are not bound to them. Sex work is valid work, you can acknowledge that while still knowing that porn is violence against women. Both exist at the same time because rape culture is so normalized in our communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slut-shaming is especially prevalent in our communities; brown boys love calling brown girls hoes, feens, and sluts for existing. Everything we do is a threat to their izzat (honor). Brown boys will get off to naked women on their screens and then go tell their girlfriends and sisters what to wear. They police the women in their life because they know that all men are, indeed, trash. They know because they happen to be one of them. You tell your sister to wear her dupatta (scarf) because you are the same man who looked at a woman lustfully as she walked down the street. You tell your girlfriend to button up her shirt because you know how predatory the male gaze is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SIMPING&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simplest form of sexism - and I say simply lightly because it is incredibly harmful and helps in climbing the sexist mountain - is literally rhetoric. Our generation has a lot of good things going for us: We have TikTok, we take care of our mental health, we’re pretty woke. But for some reason, we’re the same generation that let go of cigarettes (only for nicotine in a USB instead) faster than we let go of slut-shaming. Brown boys don’t realize that slut-shaming doesn’t have to be heard, it’s not just cat-calling, you don’t even have to call a girl a whore to her face. You just have to laugh at the rape joke your boy just told. You just have to turn a blind eye to your friend cheating on his girlfriend. You just have to say that she belongs to the streets. Think of what that means. You think just because a brown girl shows some skin, just because she is sexually liberated, and just because you can’t stand the fact that you can’t have her that she should be thrown out? It’s not just a joke. It’s suggestive of another ideology at play. Brown boys will do the same things that they think is “hoe behavior” but will never apply this double standard to themselves. Because they know they are immune to any type of backlash. So if simping means respecting women, then so be it. Be a fucking simp. Stop being nice to girls you want to sleep with and then throw all moral decency out the door. You belong to the streets, not the girl that rejected you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t think we don’t notice the fact that some brown boys hide their own sexism behind a soft boy persona. You can brand yourself a leftist and be an ally, but that performativity doesn’t do anything when you’re only doing it to appeal to women. You’ve built your base on the free labor of your female friends who taught you all the right things. The subtle sexism that exudes from self-labeled soft brown boys is typical, it’s quiet but it’s seething. You support your girlfriend being a feminist, but you want her to hold your hand while she’s saying men are trash? That’s not how it works. You are not exempt. You’ve done the bare minimum for women, congratulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many brown boys like to speak over women because they think it’s a personality trait to be sexist (and they like that their friends cheer them on for it). Brown boys have made up their minds that women’s struggles don’t even exist, so how can we ask them to be educated? You can’t sit here and tell us what YOU think real feminism is, don’t you dare talk over us who are trying to push a change through this stubborn society. You say that ‘men need to do better’ but put in zero effort to make the women you know comfortable. You don’t get a cookie for thinking you’ve never been even moderately violent towards a woman. Because chances are, you have and your girlfriend ignored it because brown girls are told to compromise isli mard aisi hi hotay hai (that’s just how boys are). Say it with me: Being nice to your mom, girlfriend, and wife isn’t being a feminist. If you still hate the ones that you think stepped out of a line set by the patriarchy, you’re a misogynist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THANK YOU FOR COMING TO MY TED TALK&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When brown boys are born, they suddenly become the center of that household, even with daughters - and yet Islam preaches the exact opposite. Brown boys are coddled, they are taught that they can do anything and they will still be defended, they are told that a woman is something to step on for their own purposes. In the city where it seems so easy to be educated and respectful despite growing up in such a household, brown boys aren’t and they refuse to be. They want their girlfriends and wives to exist solely for them, because that’s how their parent’s relationship worked. Brown boys are quick to deem this as an unnecessary gender war because nothing affects them. It’s because you don’t care because you think you’ll continue to get away with it. I’m here to tell you that you won’t.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>hiba</name></author><summary type="html">Brown boys our age engage in the most violent projections of the patriarchy. The diaspora in New York City represents a microcosm of South Asia - its vibrancy, its colorful culture, but it rears the ugly head too often, whether it be divisions of religions, nationalism, or of course, a very carefully constructed misogyny. It doesn’t come from Islam, and yet religion is used as a defense from accountability. It doesn’t come from Hinduism, and yet tradition is used as a facade to get away with it. Stop using God as your security blanket to justify your suppression of women. It has stretched from our homelands that are desperately trying to reform to no avail.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Instagram Should Not Go ‘Back to Normal’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Naja.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Instagram Should Not Go 'Back to Normal'" /><published>2020-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Naja</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Naja.html">&lt;p&gt;I am an Instagram user, just as you are and much like you I’ve noticed that my life has entrenched itself into this app. With a press of the “profile” button, I could see the display of what I want my hundreds of followers to consider to be my legitimate development. I don’t regularly talk to hundreds of people. If anything, in a single day I probably talk to a handful of close friends, maybe a past acquaintance to catch up. Or maybe I check up on family or people I’ve worked with to see how they’re fairing in these insane times. Yet, I return to this app and communicate with a void of countless people, which I honestly couldn’t have a substantive conversation with if we, by chance, met on the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This truth is reliant on our image culture that forces us to model… well models. Celebrities, snapchat influencers and child actors have shown us what is an acceptable public image, and I feel the pressures of social media have forced us to copy the behavior we’ve seen on magazine covers and movie trailers. No one is to blame for this (besides maybe our parents who let us watch countless hours of tv), and no one is innocent of it. Let’s face it, not many folks are reliant on print media and books for their main source of information about the world. Books are expensive, many people in this country can’t read English and getting news on social media is way more accessible than getting a newspaper subscription. Though countless books on public discourse have detailed the perils of receiving all media through our phones and TV screens, who is there, really, to say that this is a shameful reality, it is our major form of communication. The main way we interact with culture. With emojis and pictures that last ten seconds, we live and breath images that tell our friends and followers stuff we feel they should know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent weeks, the murders of countless Black people by police officers have been brought to light, along with many voices advocating for large-scale change in how (if at all) communities should be policed. Petitions are being shared, links to donations are being posted and great works and videos by Black people have been spread to bring awareness to the many perils that plague the United States designed to hurt Black, brown and indigenous people. Though, as a Black user, waking up to murder and violence on the app has been exhausting, it is refreshing to see so many great resources being shared by other Black people and our allies. It has also been refreshing to finally have some cohesion on the app, reminding me that our profiles and posts are coming from real, learning, people and not a series of disconnected frames of captured and manicured memories. 
In more recent times, I’ve noticed that some users (primarily white people) are returning their feed to how it was before Black Lives Matter was a global conversation. These posts are relatively sparse, and honestly funny to see how some are incapable of “reading the room” and getting the clear sense that vanity is on hiatus. This is not only testament to those people’s feelings (or, rather, their lack-there-of) around the movement, but also of Instagram’s faults as an app to be used for a universal movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not lost on anyone that people make money on Instagram. I remember a scene from the Netflix reality show “Too Hot to Handle”, a show based on the striking images of the cast, where one woman remarked on her disregard for the final cash prize because she makes so much money from her Instagram profile. Instagram is a platform where targeted advertisement brings in billions for the universally beloved Mark Zuckerberg, his friends and various businesses and campaigns that benefit from the clicks and views the platform provides. These commercials are given the same amount of space as, say, a selfie would occupy. The Washington Post account could post about an article on the current status of the crisis in Yemen or about the latest covid-19 death toll. This amount of space is also then available to you for your dog photos. All of this is in an attempt to consolidate as much information into a swipe on your phone, so you stay on the app and click on and watch the ads that get in the way. In doing so, tragedy, celebrity news and updates from our friends are given to us in one calculated gift: entertainment. So Mark Zuckerberg, his friends and a handful of kind-hearted campaigns and companies could get their fill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this is a bleak assessment of this app. I’ve also described the app as having an agenda, and I want to make it clear that all media does. The New York Times, for all its prestige in the public eye, has an incentive to publish material that wouldn’t, in any way, dissuade readers from discontinuing their subscription. This is true for all subscription-based media and its effects are often hard to notice at a glance. Instagram, in many ways, is a subscription service. We pay them by watching ads, allowing them to use our data to make better ads and complying with their user agreements so their reputation is not tarnished by individual actors. I’m making it clear that I feel like what I’ve described is wrong in the first place (and I feel like you should, too).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, I still used the app. Even when I read a post on a headline about the children in prison camps on the southern border next to a selfie from someone I don’t know next to a celebrity posting their dog next to another tragedy next to an ad next to another selfie next to a meme next to another tragedy; this goes on and on until I get bored and leave the app, to return 30 minutes later when I get bored again. This is turning tragedy into a commodity. The app gives you a package filled with horrible news, entertainment and advertisement to guarantee you keep swiping. This is an enormous time suck and has affected the way we perceive the news and the institutions around us, leaving much of the damage already done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, in a time where vanity should surely be a second thought for many of you (again, namely white people), I beg that you recognize the gravity of this moment and stop posting selfies. Not only does it show those around you that you do not care, allowing them to feel lighthearted about the situation as well; it creates an app where Black tragedy is being accompanied by blatant and damning negligence. This renders the important places to donate, petitions to sign and other learning mechanisms a form of bleak entertainment, or “tragedy porn”, to contrast with the bright and baggage-less posts from privileged users. I just cannot stand idly by and let this happen. So many people have been unlawfully killed by a country that already pays them little mind. Too many of these stories have already occurred and too much nightmarish history has happened for people to allow the advocacy of Black people and our allies to be tragedy porn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram is a very difficult place to conduct a global conversation about Blackness and Black lives, but it is possible that it becomes a place where the advocacy for disenfranchised and targeted groups becomes its first concern over vain demonstrations of oneself. I hope anyone who reads this knows I am not explicitly talking about anyone in particular, but rather a general want for things to go back to normal. I also hope that those reading this do not think I am stepping up onto a moral high-horse and preaching the truth for mindless users to listen and comply. I am also guilty of allowing tragedy to accompany my substance-less posts. I want to stress that in participating in this app, I feel that we all are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let’s face it, this pandemic, its economic and political implications and the lives affected and lost from it are going to change how this country functions for the foreseeable future. Hopefully, as activists continue to flood the streets and demand justice for the countless Black names lost by the police, the way we talk about race and see ourselves in our communities will be different for the foreseeable future. Let’s take a hard step together and shed our profile’s aesthetics and tell our followers that we will put our own personal image second to the greater movement. Instagram can be a healthy place where we achieve a fruitful balance, but we have to recognize the space we are filling up and ask ourselves if this is contributing to the betterment of those of us who are underprivileged and have already had that decision made for us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>naja</name></author><summary type="html">I am an Instagram user, just as you are and much like you I’ve noticed that my life has entrenched itself into this app. With a press of the “profile” button, I could see the display of what I want my hundreds of followers to consider to be my legitimate development. I don’t regularly talk to hundreds of people. If anything, in a single day I probably talk to a handful of close friends, maybe a past acquaintance to catch up. Or maybe I check up on family or people I’ve worked with to see how they’re fairing in these insane times. Yet, I return to this app and communicate with a void of countless people, which I honestly couldn’t have a substantive conversation with if we, by chance, met on the street.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Go Eat Some Chocolate… STAT</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Anjali.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Go Eat Some Chocolate... STAT" /><published>2020-06-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Anjali</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Anjali.html">&lt;p&gt;F**k you, 2020- the year my freshman year of college was cut short; the year I was moved away from my best friends; the year my family drove me crazy by being the only humans I saw for months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, f**k you 2020- the year developing countries struggled to deal with pandemics, epidemics, and famines; the year the unemployment rates hit all-time-highs; the year the police continued to harm innocent lives, because of the color of their skin.
With the cruelty and calamity that our phones and televisions constantly remind us of, it wouldn’t be surprising if some are questioning the entire essence of humanity. As healthcare workers continue to put their own lives on the line to save those of others; across the street, cops who swore to safeguard citizens continue to take their lives away. The dichotomy of ‘being human’ that has revealed its true colors in recent months is an inexplicable complex that can easily send you down a dwindling, downward spiral. However, the pressing nature of current events leaves no time to ponder. It’s time to shift our roles from informed bystanders to informed activists, with no time to waste.
To this end, here’s my scientific advice- go. eat. some. chocolate. Don’t get me wrong, this is NOT even remotely close to a quick fix- but it’s an essential first step that you, as a “newly born” informed activist, need to take. Let me explain.
As members of the human race, one thing we all have is a brain (even if it may not seem so these days). Our brains can be compared to the water bodies on this planet, in that we only understand about 10% of them. Surprisingly, even this 10% of understanding can give us a lot of insight into how we need to treat this ridiculously powerful organ in order to yield the best outcomes for ourselves and for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In simple, non-scientific terms, our brains are made up of a series of messengers, docks, and paths. The messengers, expectedly, are responsible for carrying messages and loading them onto or unloading them from the docks to travel down the paths. They can disguise themselves as several substances, one type being ‘endorphins’- groups of hormones that act on opiate receptors (i.e. their “allocated” docks). Through a series of scientific events, that are a bunch of blah blah unless you’re a fellow brain-fanatic (no shame), the receptors result in a feeling synonymous to that of euphoria. Chocolate, coincidentally, is a friend of endorphins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So essentially, through the simple act of biting into a chocolate bar: endorphins are triggered, and your brain undergoes some chaotic science to make you happier. If you’re a trooper, go for a run to get your dose of endorphins; but from personal experience, chocolate stands as the top contender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s join the dots. If you can remember from the days of pre-covid19 travel, the passenger announcements in airplanes would sound, “please secure your own [oxygen] mask before assisting others”. In the same light, we are living in a time when the world needs us, and we cannot afford to be in subpar shape. If we are allowing ourselves to mentally succumb to the tragedy that is an unfortunate actuality today or exposing ourselves to exhaustion- mental or physical- we will not be in a position to bring about the most effective change. While the plasticity of our brains allows them to create sentiments of optimism, they are equally capable of causing persistent pessimism. Unfortunately, our current climate has made the latter much too possible. To fully commit ourselves to fighting the bad (virus or police), we need to commit to fighting our brain’s bad tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just eat the damn chocolate, make sure you are a ‘well-oiled’ machine, and channel all your energy into helping those who need it now more than ever before.
From an amateur perspective, the only opinion towards 2020 is, simply stated, f**k you.
However, hopefully, we will look back on this year as a time when every able individual worked on their personal growth solely for the purpose of the imminently needed, joint growth. Afterall, “hindsight is 20/20”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>anjali</name></author><summary type="html">F**k you, 2020- the year my freshman year of college was cut short; the year I was moved away from my best friends; the year my family drove me crazy by being the only humans I saw for months.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">#Blackout Tuesday</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Dhruv.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="#Blackout Tuesday" /><published>2020-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Dhruv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Dhruv.html">&lt;p&gt;Online social movements frequently see unprecedented peaks of engagement, and then flame out just as quickly as they became viral. On Tuesday, June the 2nd, #BlackoutTuesday achieved such peaks, with over 24 million posts of black squares on Instagram. The intent of posting these images was to signify a pause from social media in support of the Black Lives Matter movement– not only through the solitary act of the post but also by muting all notifications and spending time that would be spent browsing social media on education and introspection about the movement. In their relentless pursuit of appearing performatively ‘woke’ to friends and followers, countless people feign interest in these movements, diluting the original noble goal of Jamila Thomas and Brianna Agyemang to use the black squares as expressions of solidarity to bring forth more discussion about widespread inequality. Unfortunately, amidst this swarm of posts, helpful information and resources for activists on the streets have gotten lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, viral social movements harness the extrinsic motivation of our desire for social conformity, thus eliciting relatively superficial engagement with the cause itself and leading to an unsustainable level of initial growth in social momentum. It is tragic that any cause must suffer from society’s restlessness to move on to the next viral trend, but Black Lives Matter has far too often found itself at the short end of this stick. A simple search on Google Trends reveals that interest in the movement waned significantly after the initial peak of the movement in July 2016 until protests broke out following the death of George Floyd. In order to prolong the success of the movement, a more meaningful connection with the cause is required. To that end, the viral nature and proper completion of the steps of the challenge offer up some merit, since education and introspection about the movement present the opportunity to build the necessary ‘intrinsic’ motivation to make the movement a sustained and reliable vehicle of public support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/max/1400/0*ScZGGXtjC69nkTH2&quot; alt=&quot;Dhruv graph photo&quot; style=&quot;float: left&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real outcomes of posts of black squares with a slew of hashtags, however, have been reductive at worst and nebulous at best. For starters, an abstruse but important objective of this act was to reduce clutter on social media so that the voices and stories of black activists could be amplified on these media. The hashtag, #BlackLivesMatter had erstwhile been used for vital information and resources for activists, and documentation of police injustices. Now, a search for #BlackLivesMatter on Instagram yields rows and rows of black squares. Thus, these well meaning posts have had quite the opposite intended effect, drowning these voices in the constant barrage of these posts. Furthermore, simply posting black squares on social media to fulfil a social obligation to conform is not enough. By any measure, education and introspection about systemic social injustice is a far more important step in the observation of #BlackoutTuesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us who are unable to directly participate in protests might want to seize this as an opportunity to do our bit– and we must recognise that our efforts to provide funds and resources to those involved can go a long way. Conversations about the long history of oppression, and systemic racism and inequality– from the boardroom to the boulevard– bring these issues to the forefront. If you must share the black square, why not add the contact information of relevant charities, and dates and locations of protests? Or recommendations and ideas for other ways people can help out? Why not extend your activism by highlighting the stories of activists and organisations that have made tremendous progress in moving towards a goal of racial equality?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Franklin once said “Justice will not be served until those who are unaffected are as outraged as those who are.” Take the anger you feel right now and channel it into educating yourself and learning more about injustice around you. Use that knowledge to change the perspectives of the people around you, whether they are your family, friends or relatives. By making the movement a collaborative effort, we can meaningfully engage in it and contribute to its growth rather than become a part of its eventual demise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must speak out against injustices that plague societies. Over the past few days, the two of us have taken the time to educate ourselves about the history of Black Lives Movements and to understand how police brutality in the United States disproportionately affects black communities. Although we lack first-hand experience of the pain and the suffering that black people and families suffer from, that shouldn’t serve as an excuse for us to shun responsibility for learning about it and empathising with their pain. This piece is an attempt to steer the conversation towards productive methods of grievance resolution and we are open to ideas which can allow us to contribute in a way that makes a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahmad Aurbery, George Floyd, Breonna Taylor, and all victims of racial injustice faced reprehensible treatment; and their deaths have rightfully sparked a global conversation on systemic and cultural racism. While energy and outrage are well spent in bringing about change in the United States, we must also raise our voices against the oppression of minority groups within our own countries and call for action to end inequality and injustice. We must feel the same empathy for disadvantaged minority groups in our own countries as we do for black people in America. Our constitutionally guaranteed rights of equality in the eyes of the law and of opportunity must transcend empty words and become lived experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dhruv</name></author><summary type="html">Online social movements frequently see unprecedented peaks of engagement, and then flame out just as quickly as they became viral. On Tuesday, June the 2nd, #BlackoutTuesday achieved such peaks, with over 24 million posts of black squares on Instagram. The intent of posting these images was to signify a pause from social media in support of the Black Lives Matter movement– not only through the solitary act of the post but also by muting all notifications and spending time that would be spent browsing social media on education and introspection about the movement. In their relentless pursuit of appearing performatively ‘woke’ to friends and followers, countless people feign interest in these movements, diluting the original noble goal of Jamila Thomas and Brianna Agyemang to use the black squares as expressions of solidarity to bring forth more discussion about widespread inequality. Unfortunately, amidst this swarm of posts, helpful information and resources for activists on the streets have gotten lost.</summary></entry></feed>